[MathType Easily write math equations from anywhere!](https://www.wiris.com/en/mathtype/) [MathType for Office Tools The easiest way to write math equations in any digital document
    
    *  
    *  
    *  
    *  
    * ](https://www.wiris.com/en/mathtype/office-tools/)    [MathType for LMS  
    The easiest way to write math equations in your Learning Management System
    
    *  
    *  
    *  
    *  ](https://www.wiris.com/en/mathtype/mathtype-for-lms/)    [MathType for Oxygen XML  
    The easiest way to write math equations in the leading XML authoring tools
    
    *  
    *  
    *  
    *  ](https://www.wiris.com/en/mathtype/mathtype-for-oxygen/)    [Arabic notation  
    Editing math formulas for arabic scientific texts](https://www.wiris.com/en/mathtype/arabic-mathematical-notations/)

    [Solutions for Education  
    Improve the quality of your math equations and chemical notations](https://www.wiris.com/en/solutions/education/) [Solutions for Publishing houses  
    Enhance your digital STEM content within your publishing house workflow and editorial solutions](https://www.wiris.com/en/solutions/publishing-houses/) [Solutions for Technical writers  
    MathType is the recommended application by the most important technical organizations and companies](https://www.wiris.com/en/solutions/technical-writers/) [Solutions for Chemistry  
    Powerful educational tools for chemistry](https://www.wiris.com/en/solutions/chemistry/) [Integrations  
    Standard and customized integrations for your app](https://www.wiris.com/en/solutions/integrations/)

1. [Home](https://www.wiris.com/en/)
2. Student Data Privacy Policy

Student Data Privacy Policy
===========================

This Privacy Policy describes WIRIS’s privacy practices in relation to information that we collect through the website [www.wiris.com](https://www.wiris.com/) operated by us from which you are accessing this Privacy Policy (the “Website”) and through the WIRIS Products made available by us for use on or through computers and mobile devices that link to this Privacy Policy.

To summarize our data privacy commitment: 

* We do not display advertising on our tools or on our website
* We do not sell or share your data with third parties to advertise or market to you. 
* We do not host third-party cookies or trackers that would allow those third parties to track you on our site.
* We use the data you share with WIRIS solely to provide you the WIRIS service, to improve it, and to keep you updated about new developments. And we only use third party services that have made the same commitment to us. 
* If you ever want to be forgotten, simply email us at [privacy@wiris.com](mailto:privacy@wiris.com) and all your data will be completely removed from our system.

* * *

### COPPA

This policy is in accordance with the U.S. Children’s Online Privacy Protection Act (“COPPA”) and Family Educational Rights and Privacy Act (FERPA), and outlines our practices world-wide regarding the personal information of all students under 13. For more information about COPPA and general tips about protecting children’s online privacy, please visit [OnGuard Online](http://www.onguardonline.gov/articles/0031-protecting-your-childs-privacy-online).

The policies outlined in this COPPA Privacy Policy are intended to supplement the information appearing in our general Privacy Policy. Where the COPPA Privacy Policy conflicts with our general Privacy Policy concerning information about a Child, the terms of this COPPA Privacy Policy will prevail over our general Privacy Policy.

* * *

### Teachers or schools consent in lieu of a parent

With regard to school-based activities, COPPA allows teachers and school administrators to act in the stead of parents to provide consent for the collection of personal information from children. Schools should always notify parents about these activities.

WIRIS collects limited personal information from students where that student’s school, district, or teacher has provided access to the WIRIS service, which collects personal information solely for the use and benefit of the learning environment.  

If you are accessing WIRIS Tools on behalf of a Class, School or District, you represent and warrant that you are solely responsible for complying with the Child Online Privacy Protection Act (COPPA) requirement to secure parental consent for accessing applications which require personal information from children under 13.

* * *

### Review and Deletion of Personal Information

Under FERPA regulations, Parents have the right to refuse the site further contact with their child and to have access to their child’s school record information and to have it deleted by contacting the school administrator.

If you are a parent and would like more information on parental rights with respect to a child’s educational record under the U.S. Family Educational Rights and Privacy Act (FERPA), please visit the [FERPA site](http://www.ed.gov/policy/gen/guid/fpco/ferpa/index.html). 

If you are the parent and guardian of a student using WIRIS Software, and cease to agree with WIRIS’s terms of use and privacy policy at some point in the future, you may opt-out by contacting the WIRIS subscriber (typically your school) contact us directly at [privacy@wiris.com](mailto:privacy@wiris.com).

If you wish to review your or your student’s or your child’s personally identifiable information stored by WIRIS, you may email us your request at [privacy@wiris.com](mailto:privacy@wiris.com) . We will respond to your request within 30 days.

If your or your student’s or your child’s personally identifiable information changes, or if you no longer desire our service, you may correct, update, or delete it, email us at [privacy@wiris.com](mailto:privacy@wiris.com). We will respond to your request within 30 days.

We will retain your information only for as long as your account is active or as needed to provide you services. If you wish to cancel your account or request that we no longer use your information to provide you services, contact us at [support@wiris.com](mailto:support@wiris.com). We will only retain and use your information as necessary to comply with our legal obligations.

In any correspondence such as e-mail or mail, please include the children email, the school or organization, and the teacher or parent’s email address and telephone number. To protect children’s privacy and security, we will take reasonable steps to help verify a teacher or parent’s identity before granting access to any personal information.

* * *

### Personal information stored

In order to use WIRIS desktop products , the users give their email address voluntarily to us. Users also have the option to use WIRIS products by registering with their Google Document Accounts.In this option, users have to share their email address with WIRIS because they have to sign in in their Google account in order to use WIRIS products which are for Google Documents usage.

We do not store any other information from the users. 

Please note that children can choose whether to share this information with us, but certain features may not function without it. As a result, children may not be able to access certain features if required information has not been provided. We will not require a child to provide more information than is reasonably necessary in order to use our services, and we use this personal data for no other purpose than providing the service to the user.

WIRIS collects limited personal information from students only where that student’s school, district, or teacher has engaged with WIRIS to collect personal information for the use and benefit of the learning environment. This information is not shared outside of the school or with any third parties except those needed for the provision of the service as outlined in this policy. 

Teachers or students can record formulas, questions and answers in our products in our system. All those contents are anonymous in our systems.  None of this information is shared with any third parties.

* * *

### Cookies and similar technologies used

Technologies such as cookies, beacons, tags and scripts are used by WIRIS. These technologies are used to make it easier for you to navigate our tools, analyzing trends, administering the site, tracking users’ movements throughout the site and to gather usage information about our user base as a whole. We may receive reports based on the use of these technologies by these companies on an individual as well as aggregated basis.

As true of most Web Sites, we gather certain information automatically and store it in log files. This information may include internet protocol (IP) addresses, browser type, internet service provider (ISP), referring/exit pages, operating system, date/time stamp, and/or clickstream data. We do not link this automatically-collected data to other information we collect about you.

WIRIS collects and analyzes data on how the service is used in the aggregate for the purpose of improving and enhancing its service. WIRIS does not analyze information on how particular individuals use the service as part of general reporting procedures or in the usual course of business. However, information on individual usage of the system, including but not limited to individual IP addresses, may be analyzed on a case-specific basis to resolve a technical difficulty or to assist in resolving or investigating any misuse of the service;

* * *

### Is the Personal Information Secure?

We endeavor to protect information we hold in our records, but we cannot guarantee complete security. The transmission of information via the Internet is not completely secure. Unauthorized entry or use, hardware or software failure, and other factors, may compromise the security of user information at any time.

When you enter your information on our site we encrypt the transmission of that information using transport layer security (TLS). Firewalls are used to segregate application tiers and provide strict controls on access to resources within our networks. Your data is also encrypted at rest on the servers hosted by our cloud services partner Google Cloud Platform, which we selected because of their compliance with COPPA, and their stringent security measures, including compliance with the following certifications and third-party attestations:

Outages, attacks, unauthorized use, or other factors may compromise the security of user information at any time. In the event of a security breach, we will notify you by posting on the WIRIS website and notifying you by email using the email address on your account within 72 hours of WIRIS becoming aware of such breach. For EU residents, notification to the WIRIS Supervisory Authority shall be made within the same time period.

* * *

### Third Party Service Providers used

We work with a number of third-party service providers to help improve the quality of our service. We have contracts with these third parties which guarantee that they do not share your information with any other third parties and protect the data at least the same level as we do ourselves.

**WIRIS uses the following third-party services:** 

**Google Ads:** this tool helps us publishing our ads to meaningful audiences based on the visits to our websites

**Google Analytics, Hotjar:** these cookies help us understand and improve our users’ experience of our websites

 **Google Tag Manager**: a technical solution for managing the cookies detailed on this page

**Facebook Pixel, Quora Pixel, Twitter, Outbrain Pixel:** conversion tracking and remarketing.

We will only contract with future service providers that are consistent with this policy or allow users a choice to send information to the future provider.For more information on any of these third parties please contact us at: [privacy@wiris.com](mailto:privacy@wiris.com)

* * *

### Changes to this Policy

We reserve the right to amend this Privacy Policy at any time. Please check this page periodically for changes.  If we intend to make a material change in the collection, use, or disclosure practices with respect to a Child’s previously-collected personal information to which a school or district has previously has consented, we will contact by email to obtain the consent of the school, district, teacher or parent who registered for the service in connection with the child to such changes.

* * *

### Disclosure and Permissions

We do not disclose personal information collected from Children to third parties other than to persons who provide support for the operations of the service and who do not use the information for any other purpose, except as follows:

* Parents
* Teachers & school administrators

We may disclose any and all personal information collected from a Child to the parent or teacher who registered for the service in connection with such Child. 

We may disclose your or your child’s personally identifiable information in connection with business transfers and purchases. As we continue to develop our business we may buy or sell business divisions or companies, we may merge or combine with another company, or our company itself and/or all or a significant part of its assets may be acquired by another company. We may provide any information we have to a potential counter-party in any such potential transaction. If such a transaction is completed, your or your child’s personally identifiable information may be one of the transferred and shared business assets. In the event that information is shared in this manner, notice will be posted on our Site. In this event this privacy policy will continue to apply unless we contact you and ask you to opt in to any changes before they are implemented.

We reserve the right to disclose your or your child’s personally identifiable information as required by law and when we believe that disclosure is necessary to protect our rights and/or to comply with a judicial proceeding, court order, or legal process served on our Website.

* * *

### Links to Other Sites

If you click on a link to a third-party site, you will leave www.wiris.com and be redirected to the site you selected. Because we cannot control the activities of third parties, we cannot accept responsibility for any use of your personally identifiable information by such third parties, and we cannot guarantee that they will adhere to the same privacy practices as www.wiris.com We encourage you to review the privacy statements of any other service provider from whom you request services. If you visit a third-party website that is linked to the www.wiris.com site, you should read that site’s privacy statement before providing any personally identifiable information.

* * *

### Contact

Have questions or concerns about our services and privacy? Contact us at [privacy@wiris.com](mailto:privacy@wiris.com)

**Maths for More S.L.**

Roger de Flor 223  
08025 Barcelona  
SPAIN

Making people’s STEM work more meaningful

        * [MathType for Microsoft 365: The equation editor for Word and PowerPoint](https://www.wiris.com/en/mathtype/microsoft-office/)

* Cookie Settings
* © Wiris 2024
